hpb.com 2019-05-18

# Privacy Policy | Half Price Books

### Privacy Policy

Half Price Books, Records, Magazines, Incorporated and its affiliates (“HPB”) are committed to respecting the privacy of our customers and website visitors. This Privacy Policy applies to personal information provided or obtained through our website (the “Site”), including any mobile applications that we may offer, and on certain social media webpages, including our Facebook Page (“Social Media Pages”).

Please note that information or other content submitted on any website linked to the Site or a Social Media Page is subject to the terms of the privacy policy applicable to such website, and not the terms of this Privacy Policy. Please also note that we do not have control over the data collection and use practices of others with respect to information that you submit on a social media site – thus, the provisions of this Privacy Policy pertaining to Social Media Pages only apply to information submitted directly to us by or through a social media site.

#### Information We Collect

Contact Information. When you contact us using one of our online contact forms, or by sending us any communication through the contact methods provided on the Site, we receive the messages you send (including any personal information contained therein) as well as the personal information you provide, such as your name, phone number, and e-mail address. When you provide such information, we may use it for the purpose for which it was provided, as well as in any manner consistent with this Privacy Policy. 

Transactional Information. We generate and collect information concerning you in connection with offering and providing services and merchandise you request or order, including information generated or received in connection with your transactions with us. This may include information that you provide for processing and shipping purposes, such as name, phone number, shipping address, billing address, e-mail address, and credit or debit card information. We may share this information with service providers and third parties as necessary to process your transactions (such as shipping a book to the appropriate address). The forwarding of your personal information in connection with purchases through the Site of merchandise offered by third-party sellers is further addressed in the “How We Use and Share Information” section below. 

Some of our electronic transactions are made using an approved postal service provider who assigns a unique identifier to the transaction as part of the process. Such identifier, and the associated customer name, shipping and billing addresses, telephone number, e-mail address, and other relevant information may be provided to the U.S. Postal Service upon request or in connection with a legal investigation or requirement.

Job Application Information. We collect names, addresses, phone numbers, job history, references, and other information you submit if you use the Site to apply for employment with HPB. Such information is used for purposes of evaluating your application, as further described on the corresponding pages of the Site. 

Your Account. If you set up an account for use on our Site, we will collect information from you as necessary to support your use of the account and to process transactions you make using the account. In addition, when you create an account, you will be required to create a username and password. It is your responsibility to maintain the confidentiality and security of your account username and password. 

Log Data. When you access and use our Site, we may automatically record information concerning your activity on the Site. This may include your IP address or other identifier, your browser type, the types of information you search for and view on our Site, locale preferences, and your mobile carrier. If you arrived at our Site by clicking on an advertisement or promotion on another website, we may also take note of the web page you visited before you came to our Site. 

Cookies. A “cookie” is a small data file that is transferred to your browser or mobile device through the Site. Our Site uses cookies to collect information in order to study, enhance and improve the use and capabilities of our Site. The information collected, associated, or analyzed through this practice may include your name, physical address, e-mail address, information concerning your browser, IP address, and device-identifying information. We also use cookies to enable certain features of our Site, and to preserve your preferences and customize your experience when you visit and return to the Site. We may permit one or more service providers to place cookies on the Site in order to assist us in making recommendations for purchases to you. Most browsers provide controls whereby you can choose to block receipt of cookies, to delete cookies, or to be prompted before cookies are received. Please note that, if you delete or choose not to receive cookies from our Site, the functionality of the Site may be impaired. To find out more about cookies, including how to manage or delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org.](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

Third Party Data Collection/Online Tracking. We may use third-party advertising services to serve ads when you visit the Site, and we use third-party analytics services to help us understand and improve the usage of the Site and the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. These services currently include but may not be limited to Google Analytics. The providers of these services may use your IP address or an anonymous identifier as well as certain information from your browser, together with other non-personal information about your visits to our Site and other websites, in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you on our Site and other websites and/or to provide analytical information for our Site and other websites. If you would like more information about advertising networks, including choices about the use of information by Google and other companies for multi-site advertising purposes, go to www.networkadvertising.org and www.networkadvertising.org/choices/. Also, Google offers a Google Analytics browser add-on (designed to be compatible only with certain browsers) to provide website visitors the ability to prevent their data from being collected and used by Google Analytics. That add-on may be obtained here: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en; and other privacy controls are available here: www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html. 

We use a third-party payment processor in the course of processing your orders or requests. This processor may prepare, use, and/or share with third parties aggregated, non-personally identifiable information derived from transaction information of all of our customers, or specific groups of our customers. In addition, we have engaged a third-party service provider for shipping purposes to facilitate efficient and accurate use and printing of postage. That service provider may receive, access, use, and disclose certain limited personal information in furtherance of its responsibilities as a postage and shipment services provider.

Currently, various Internet browsers offer a “do not track” or “DNT” option that uses a DNT header to indicate the DNT preference setting on the browser. HPB does not currently commit to responding to browsers’ DNT signals with respect to the Site, in part because no common industry standard for DNT has been adopted by industry groups, technology companies, or regulators, including no consistent standard of interpreting user intent. HPB takes privacy and meaningful choice seriously and will continue to monitor pertinent developments in this area.

We do not permit our third-party service providers to collect information from the Site for other websites or for their own purposes other than as described in this section.

Social Media Features. The Site includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button. These features may collect your IP address and which page you are visiting on the Site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Actions you take in connection with social media features may be reflected in a manner visible to others; for example, if you “Like” us on Facebook, others may be able to see that you have done so. 

Social Media Pages. The collection and use of information on social media websites and applications is governed by their own privacy policies. Please remember that any information posted on the Half Price Books Page on Facebook (“HPB Facebook Page”) or on other social media pages or channels is public. 

We may receive personal information from a social media site platform or application when you connect through a social media feed, post content, or otherwise interact with us using social media tools. For example, we may receive basic Facebook account information (name, e-mail, gender, birthday, current city, and profile picture URL) through the HPB Facebook Page. Also, when you “like,” “subscribe to,” or send a “tweet” to us through a social media channel, we may receive your username, handle, and any other available personal information from the social media site or application. All information received from social media sites and applications is treated and used in the same manner and for the same purposes as described in this Policy with respect to similar information we obtain through the Site.

Other Websites. As described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, we may collect certain information through our Social Media Pages and we may collect originating information associated with a link or advertisement that leads you to our Site or a Social Media Page. In other respects, we do not collect personally identifiable information about your online activities on third-party websites or online services. 

Geo-Location Information. Many mobile devices permit applications to access real-time location-based information. We may collect and use that information, with your consent, in order to enhance the features and functionality of our mobile applications and service offerings. With respect to non-mobile devices, some of the information we collect, such as IP addresses, may be used to estimate an approximate location of the device you are using to access our Site. 

#### How We Use and Share Personal Information

We use personal information to carry out requested transactions, to provide services, and to improve our Site and our service and merchandise offerings. We may use some of the information that we collect concerning you in order to present you with information concerning services or merchandise that may be of interest to you. For example, we may tailor our marketing efforts based on the types of services and merchandise you purchase, the merchandise in which you demonstrate an interest, and your use of our Site. Please note that we will separately obtain express or implied consent from you before contacting you whenever we are required to do so by law (such as the Canadian “anti-spam” law). In addition, we may retain and use communications, transaction details, your IP address, and identifying information in order to maintain audit trails for security purposes. 

We may provide personal information to third-party providers of goods and services who assist us in maintaining the Site and in other aspects of our business operations. We require that those providers use personal information only for that purpose, and we also require assurances that they will appropriately protect personal information entrusted to them.

When you use the Site to order merchandise from a third-party seller, we will collect your payment and share your personal information, excluding payment card information, with the third-party seller for the purposes of fulfilling your order, handling related inquiries, or forwarding comments concerning your order. We may also share such information with Monsoon Commerce, which acts as an intermediary for the third-party seller marketplace. The third-party sellers and Monsoon Commerce may use the personal information that we provide only for the purposes of fulfilling orders and for handling related inquiries.

If you no longer wish to receive email communication from Half Price Books, please click the unsubscribe link in the footer of every email we send or make changes to your subscription preferences in your HPB.com account.

#### Protecting Personal Information

We are committed to maintaining the security of personal information. We employ reasonable security measures to secure and protect the information we receive. Please remember, though, that neither the Internet nor any method of electronic transmission or storage is 100% secure.

#### Disclosure Policy

We disclose personal information as necessary to operate our business, such as in connection with providing assistance and merchandise to you or processing your transactions. We also may disclose information concerning you if required to do so by law or if we believe that such action is necessary to comply with a legal obligation or to protect and defend our rights or property, or those of others.

#### Sales, Mergers, and Acquisitions

In the event of a sale or other transfer of ownership of one or more of our locations or other business units to a third party (whether by private sale, through operation of law, as part of a divestiture plan, or otherwise), we will provide personal information and transaction history associated with each such location or business unit to the persons and/or entities assuming control of such location or business unit.

#### Links

The Site may contain links to other websites, and other websites may link to the Site. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites. Whenever you visit another website – via a link from the Site or otherwise – you should review the privacy policy of that other website. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information provided or obtained on or through the Site and to information submitted directly to us by or through a social media site.

#### No Use by Children Under the Age of 18

We are committed to complying with all applicable laws and regulations regarding the collection, storage and use of personal information of minors under the age of 18, including the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998.

Products that may commonly be used by minors under the age of 18, like textbooks or children’s books, are marketed through the Site and in our stores. However, products, including products for children, may be purchased on the Site only by adults. Persons under the age of 18 may only review the Site, and may do so only with the involvement of a parent or guardian.

We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from children under the age of 18 or knowingly allow such persons to register for an online account or to place orders or provide personal information through the Site. If we learn that someone under the age of 18 has provided any personal information through the Site, we will remove and permanently delete that information as soon as reasonably possible.

If you are a parent or guardian who believes that your minor under the age of 18 has submitted personal information or other information to us without your consent, please contact [privacy@hpb.com](mailto:privacy@hpb.com). Once we verify that you are the parent or legal guardian, we will cooperate with you to discuss what, if any, personal information we have collected about your child and how that information may have been shared or used. 

#### How to Contact Us

Customer questions, comments and feedback are very important to us. For privacy-related issues, click here to contact us via e-mail, or write to us at: 5803 East Northwest Highway Dallas, TX 75231. 

#### Your California Privacy Rights

Under California’s “Shine the Light” law, California residents who provide personal information in connection with purchasing products or services from us may make a request concerning personal information, if any, that we have shared with other businesses for their own direct marketing purposes. Such a request may be made by sending an e-mail message to [privacy@hpb.com](mailto:privacy@hpb.com?subject=Request%20for%20California%20Privacy%20Information) with “Request for California Privacy Information” in the subject line of the message. In response to such a request, we will provide information as required by the California law for the previous calendar year concerning such other businesses and the categories of personal information, if any, that we have shared with them. 

#### Notification of Changes to Policy

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy. Whenever we decide to change this Policy, notice of the change will be posted on the Site for a reasonable period of time. Nevertheless, you should review the Privacy Policy from time to time to be sure you are aware of the most recent version. We will use information only in accordance with the Privacy Policy in effect at the time the information was collected.

Effective March 10, 2015
